# **BRIDGET HASS**

## bridgethass@gmail.com| 541.231.0303

Skilled in developing open, reproducible workflows for remote sensing data processing and analysis. Experienced in creating and teaching open-source live coding tutorials for working with aerial lidar and hyperspectral data to support ecological research applications.

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## 2016-PRESENT

**Remote Sensing Data Scientist,** National Ecological Observatory Network (NEON) Airborne Observation Platform (AOP), Battelle Memorial Institute

- Develop automated, version-controlled workflows for remote sensing data processing to generate open access aerial lidar, hyperspectral, and camera data products
- Create and teach live-coding tutorials in Python Jupyter Notebooks on reproducible remote sensing data processing and analysis (using open NEON data)
- Lead field campaigns for lidar validation and hyperspectral radiometric calibration

#### 2012-2015

## Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant, Oregon State University

- Thesis on subduction zone heat flow modeling for the International Ocean Drilling Program (IODP) Costa Rica Seismogenesis Project (CRISP). Published findings in G<sup>3</sup> (Geochemistry, Geophysics, Geosystems)
- Consulted on international marine oil exploration cruises; collected, processed, and analyzed marine heat flow data for use in models to locate offshore petroleum reservoirs
- Taught undergraduate laboratory courses in geology, geophysics, and atmospheric science

#### 2011-2012

Marine Geophysical Technician, Scripps Institution of Oceanography, University of California, San Diego

- Assembled, maintained, repaired, and assisted with shipboard operations of marine geophysical instruments including multichannel seismic reflection, magnetometers, and echosounders on scientific research cruises

### **EDUCATION**

#### **JUNE 2015**

## M.S., Oregon State University

- Degree: Earth, Ocean, and Atmospheric Science, Concentration: Marine Geophysics
- Research projects in seismology and heat flow

#### **MAY 2010**

## **B.S., Cornell University**

- Degree in Science of Earth Systems, College of Engineering
- Honors thesis on seismic receiver functions to map geothermal profile of New Mexico

## **OPEN-SOURCE TRAINING**

**OCT 2020** 

**Google Earth Engine for Ecology and Conservation** – Organization for Tropical Studies

Two-week online course on using GEE for ecological applications.

**FEB-JUNE 2020** 

**Data Science Nanodegree** – Udacity

4 month, 160 hour training in Data Science principals using Python to generate data pipelines, software engineering principles, machine learning, and recommendation systems

FEB 2020

Foundations for Open Science Skills - CyVerse, University of Arizona

Week long workshop on FAIR data principals, open science skills, reproducible research, and version control in GitHub

**JAN 2017** 

**Reproducible Science Curriculum Hackathon** – Berkeley Institute for Data Science Three day Hackathon to generate a prototype of a Data Carpentry workshop on reproducible science principals using Python Jupyter Notebooks

## TEACHING & WORKSHOP EXPERIENCE

2020 & 2021

**CyVerse-NEON AOP Workshops and Webinars** 

**Developer and Instructor**: *CyVerse-NEON Airborne Observation Platform Workshop* Open source tools in R, Python (Nov 2020), and Google Earth Engine (Nov 2021) for working with NEON AOP data in the CyVerse computing environment.

**Guest Instructor**: Bright Lights, Big Data: Leverage NEON's Datasets and Resources https://cyverse.org/webinar-NEON

2017 & 2018

**NEON Remote Sensing Data Institutes** 

Developed and taught live-coding materials for week-long intensive workshop on creating reproducible workflows using NEON remote sensing data in Python Jupyter Notebooks. <a href="https://www.neonscience.org/resources/learning-hub/workshops/neon-data-institute-2018-remote-sensing-reproducible-workflows">https://www.neonscience.org/resources/learning-hub/workshops/neon-data-institute-2018-remote-sensing-reproducible-workflows</a>

## LINKS

**LinkedIn:** www.linkedin.com/in/bridget-hass

**GitHub:** https://github.com/bridgethass

https://github.com/NEONScience/NEON-Data-Skills (contributor)